# Michael K. (Mike) Null

501-712-6723 michael.null@bpmw.net 1705 Wildflower Ln, Wylie TX 75098

## **Profile**

Freelance .Net developer available for web and database projects. Experienced French-English interpreter, translator and transcriber available for translation and website localization for the U.S., especially in the aerospace and IT fields.

Traducteur expérimenté disponible pour projets traduction de documents ou localisation de sites-web, en particulier dans les domaines de l'aerospace et l'informatique.

## Experience

### TEST ENGINEER 3, L-3 COMMUNICATIONS, GREENVILLE TX - SEPTEMBER 2015-PRESENT

Systems Engineering position as part of a team that supports the design, development, test, and integration of the maintenance and support systems for ISR aircraft platforms and ground systems.

### .NET ENGINEERING STUDENT, THE IRON YARD, LITTLE ROCK, AR-JUNE -SEPTEMBER 2015

Studied C#, Javascript, HTML/CSS and SQL programming languages, object-oriented programming principles and source control. Used Microsoft Visual Studio 2015. Produced several website and database projects culminating in a final project featuring a complex data model, SQL database and responsive, dynamic HTML front-end interface using Angular JS and Bootstrap.

### SECTION CHIEF, US AIR FORCE, MILDENHALL UK - 1991-2011

Progressed from apprentice mechanic to intelligence analysis section chief. Supervised up to twenty highly trained people. Earned cash awards for re-writing Air Force wide aircraft maintenance procedures. Awarded Senior NCO of the Quarter and NCO of the Month.

#### INTERPRETER/TRANSLATOR AND FACTOTUM, BEAUDET AVIATION, LITTLE ROCK ARKANSAS - 2014

Key role in launching the company's first US workshop. Took on purchasing, bookkeeping and Human Resources responsibilities.

## SENIOR BILINGUAL CALL CENTER AGENT, FIS GLOBAL, LITTLE ROCK ARKANSAS – 2011-2013

The primary go-to example to demonstrate customer service professionalism to clients. Stood out in reliability, effectiveness and compassion. Took on the floor supervisor role and trained as a team lead. Was retained when the company eliminated work section in a major layoff. Left to pursue a graduate degree to take on roles with higher levels of responsibility.

# Michael K. (Mike) Null

501-712-6723 michael.null@bpmw.net 501 Oneida St, Jacksonville AR 72076

## **Education and Certification**

THE IRON YARD .NET ENGINEERING COURSE, JUNE-SEPTEMBER 2015
MASTER OF BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION—UNIVERSITY OF CENTRAL ARKANSAS, 2014, GPA 4.0

coursework in economics, finance, operations management and entrepreneurship

### ASSOCIATE IN APPLIED SCIENCE-COMMUNITY COLLEGE OF THE AIR FORCE, 1998

Aircraft Systems Maintenance Technology

CERTIFIED MANAGER-ICPM, JUNE 2015 MEMBER OF ASQ

# Relevant Experience and Skills

#### **LEADERSHIP AND MANAGEMENT**

Held management roles from 1996 to 2011 leading teams of up to twenty–including supervising supervisors, managing projects and programs, writing personnel evaluations. Received manager of the quarter award in 2008 among many other tokens of recognition. Earned Certified Manager certification from ICPM in 2015.

## LANGUAGE SKILLS

French: Bilingual Proficiency-ILR score 2011: 3 Reading, 3 Listening

Arabic: Limited Working Proficiency-ILR score 2011: 2+ Reading, 3 Listening

English: Native

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

.Net Engineering

Microsoft Visual Studio

Web Design

C#

**Object Oriented Programming** 

**Javascript**